foreign
[Music]
hungry foreign
America
it's your time
I continuous make jokes sorry
perfect do you want to
sure
foreign
yes thank you very much for introducing
also thank you very much for inviting I
had a lot of very exciting meetings so
thank you for that I really appreciate
it on Friday and yesterday so and one
notable thing is really that you know
what Dynamics is
very simple because in many parts of the
world people don't really know what
Dynamics is
um so we have a broad research program
which really goes about brain mind
connection and I show you today one
particular line of that and that
concerns psychiatry
so we have this and I will explain this
is
um model of brain mind connection
um that's a special Temple connection
and from there we basically uh
investigate also different psychiatric
phenomena
and the main idea here is for psychology
is really
that we can say this goes into the sum
of the tentatively the mechanism of
course I look at the computational
people and they say this is not
mechanism what you're talking about and
they write probably least tentative and
second that that also carries clinical
significance meaning diagnostic markers
and therapy suggestions to which I come
at the end and I think that's why we
really convert that you pursue a similar
line of research so fire okay so thank
you very much I didn't know that you do
the job then you want to talk for me
okay good so the monkey is and that's a
little bit conceptual background so that
you see where I'm coming from because
that's very important to understand or
not misunderstand what I'm saying so
here uh what we often do in current
Neuroscience uh it's really we are on
the surface of the iceberg we look
of certain cognitive functions attention
working memory perception motor action
which are observable to the outside
and then we look for new correlates and
then firstly that's the brilliant and
said okay there's a computational
mechanism predictive coding active
infant generative model which I would
say
operate here
and then you say no no no no this is not
really true then you would say uh Frozen
comes with the argument of theology but
you would say the free energy should be
between here and here where it directly
interfaces to the water but that's not
true the free energy is calculated at
the sum total of the prediction error so
it's ultimately here so you need to
really go into some of the operational
details so I'm looking here why because
I think we need to go back to the deeper
layers of the brain where it directly
interface or aligns you will hear that
often or in quotes
it's direct environmental input so again
EAC encoding here is a decoding of what
is encoded yeah and I'm looking here and
you will see this there's a constant
scene of my uh talk and it's important
for Psychiatry and also I think it
provides new views on the modeling so
you will see we do a lot of input
modeling so and what characterizes these
deeper layers where I say these are key
for the mind for the brain mind
connection
so that's really a different approach
when you look in the current
Neuroscience in the history of
psychology and you'll say they always
look for the mind up here I can't can't
even reach it yeah uh they always look
here I look here so I go backwards
rather than forwards next one
so that's basically an overview
um so I first before going into the
crisis of Psychiatry uh that I go into
the special Temple approach what it is
then I'll show you two examples of the
spatial temporal approach depression
with the speed disturbance I know this
is all very strange for you if you're
coming from cognitive psychology or
cognitive behavior therapy or from
biological Psychiatry what is speed it's
trivial runs schizophrenia as a temple
Precision disturbance and you will see I
try to assemble a lot of evidence for
that and then I come to the conclusions
from mechanism to diagnosis and therapy
next one
so a very short brief in Psychology we
even face more of a crisis than a
neurology and where you're dealing with
uh because next one
um so normally don't know this
a quarter of our mental disorder of all
disorders are mental disorders
yeah I mean sorry to say the numbers for
dementia are low I think it's 20 30
million compared to depressional anxiety
is 80 milligrams look at the funding
just as a side note yeah the discrepancy
so we have to change that because uh
the incidence of mental health disorders
is increasing
in particular very alarming among young
people
in particular after the coffee so this
is not so in 10 years there was an
estimate from the who it will be by 30
of all physical diseases not just 25 and
when you ask around it's amazing I
remember that last year in October there
was an article in the in the in the
Canadian newspaper about our work we
were on front page and in the evening I
went to the supermarket and brought the
newspaper
and then the cashier looked at me no
this is you I said she's asking what are
you doing yes I'm dealing with anxiety
and breathing service oh I need that too
yeah so even the cashier but just by
chance is unbelievable yeah uh and
eighty percent of many of them are
anxiety and depression yeah so it's it's
uh really tendency increasing so we
focus our main focus here for the sake
of pragmatism but it will be extended in
the future is anxiety disorders
depression uh schizophrenia bipolar
disorder but we'll also include for
instance post-traumatic stress disorder
because it's very important next one
so uh what is the challenge of treating
mental health disorder we have no
markers we don't even have neurological
Sciences you have you have some symptoms
which uh many psychiatrists interpret in
different ways so there's a saying if
you attend psychiatrist and one patient
you have 20 diagnosis yeah so it's
really it's it's very problematic
there's a lot of discussion about
classification DSM some of you might
heard that the alternative systems yeah
so that's on the diagnostic side so we
have more diagnostic markers
yeah so it's a catastrophe then
depending upon your orientation where
you're psychodynamic or whether you're
Freudian or Union or whether you're
biological you're diagnosed different
the catastrophe
and that continues with the drugs I'm
not against drug treatment so if there's
some pharmaceutical company people here
fair but the drugs are they suppress the
whole brain
they're not selective so imagine if you
have a a broken bone
you're in your lower right leg
and you need to do some physiotherapy in
order to keep the rest the the upper
side and the other leg intact now the
doctor puts a cast on both legs up to
your body so that's basically what we as
psychiatrists do
yeah it was many drugs
so and we have a lot of trial and other
treatments and of course I don't need to
lead to a lot of suffering next one
so why is that because we don't know the
mechanism we have no idea about how this
we see abnormal neuronal activity on a
group level
many results cannot be replicated let
alone individual prediction you have
data sets with thousand ten thousand of
subjects let's say in imaging or genetic
in media music
so the question is whether you just
increase your case numbers and use more
machine learning methods or whether you
think about your model of your disease
on which you base your investigations so
you will see that I go the letter way
yeah and I don't need to say the other
way is often technology latest is now
computational Psychiatry we get into
mechanism but it's the same old model
yeah everyone they have the same crisis
they don't yield markers
next one
um so this is clear unlike in Physical
Medicine maybe even worse than you
dementia guys next one
so here we summarize the distance from a
recent paper which will come out in
schizophrenia bulletin so it's a twofold
it's a crisis of mechanism we don't
really understand the neuronal and
computational mechanism of the
psychopathological certainly yes we have
the predictive coding we have empirical
prior but these are unspecific changes
across all disorders
empirical prior is abnormal or not yeah
so it's a real lack of specificity as
brilliant as resistance model is and I
would really say it's a brilliant thing
so we have no biomarkers here on the
left I'm here
um that's also a stagnation in the
development of new psychotropic drugs
and other therapies yeah so now many
psychiatrists just try out some therapy
yeah because that's it that you you get
grants but again it's a blind so some
patients will benefit some not and the
results are usually immediate forget it
and then that's a specific twist I would
like to add as I'm originally from
Germany Continental European it's a
crisis of subjectivity
because what these psychiatric disorders
are essentially
subjective disorders it's your
experience so I can hear voices but okay
I can function very well that the way I
experience them subjectively that's the
keys yeah so auditory hallucination is a
completely unspecific symptom you have
it in dementia often in Progressive
stages of dementia you have auditory
hallucination yeah
and
here here there we are so same thing
here so that's why we really need to
move the mechanism with the subjectivity
and that's the background question for
the approach I'm doing next one
so what we link is this what we miss is
this triangle between symptoms brain and
experience and that's what I call among
others common currency
that's the key that's basically now if
you're not interested in the solution
you can go home now and just say that's
what I'm talking about next one
okay I say next one so now I show you a
little bit what's the spatial Temple
approaches
so it has his roots also in philosophy
because I'm also philosopher I don't
want to go into philosophy now but I
want to tell you one hidden preser
positions in current neuroscience and
psychiatry
that's the present position of what I
call the presupposition of specialness
so
the mind and mental features and
Consciousness and self are something
special
there's a special mechanism in the brain
added on to the other non-special
mechanisms
so here in philosophy you have is this
the red stuff it's reflective and
phenomenal Consciousness and I block
access to normal consciously I
explicated that for the Consciousness
Theory but it goes the same for the self
and all other mental features and we see
here in the Consciousness Theory uh
integrated information it's a special
mechanism slash integration
on top of the non-integration in the
brain that's completely stupid sorry I
hope there's no IIT proponent here yeah
okay there's a special embodiment and
then we have Consciousness as if the
brain is not always embodied only the
upper part of the iceberg has
information integration only the other
part is
yeah uh enter a higher order sort Theory
now Rosenthal uh Global neural workspace
and this is a recurrent processing
Theory by um
yeah and then of course here is the
brain and that person really says the
only model of brain is basically really
the friction Theory and I think also
Marcus rack is somewhat but it's not
well elaborated his interesting model
yeah and so this is and that's a month
but I don't need to tell you is for
those who are Western philosophy that's
basically a continuation of streetcar
with the Neuroscience it's a Cartesian
Neuroscience it's a dualism
yeah so there is something special to
the mind and let's place it yeah okay
now the people say no no no no not after
you cannot say this
but you will assume something special in
The Breakfast itself that's neuronic
Cartesian next one
yeah and that leads to all the problems
discussed in current philosophy the
icons is the gap of contingency uh it's
the explanatory Gap problem it's a hard
problem David Chamas and so on and so
forth yeah Big Splash no output sorry
next one
uh I will be fast so guys good so next
one I told you okay now so what I do I
say okay maybe we should not look for
the difference we look for something
similar what is shared again and this is
it it sounds strange and it sounds very
metaphysical no it's basically what when
you look into the history of science
that's what people do they look for
something similar David looked for what
different speeches share what's a human
shared with the monsoon
thank you
um so what humans and non-humans share I
mean from a Christian perspective was a
catastrophe yeah uh
looked for what the Earth share with the
other planets in the universe not what
makes it special what makes it different
so this is really and you see in some of
my books I claim for a companion term
but this so I look for the similarity
next one
so now what is similar so I always like
this quote uh by Nikola Tesla so it was
an engineer uh 1920th Century or from
former Yugoslavia and then he went to
New York and look at his uh Google very
interesting guy a very interesting very
idiosyncratic and there's no I think
there's no coincidence that uh Tesla uh
that have a mask Elon Musk name discuss
Tesla I think they share the Innovation
the really creative capacity which is
amazing but also the idiosyncrasies in
the personalities so that is really it's
amazing so what he said this beautiful
thing if you want to find the secrets of
the universe think in terms of energy
frequency vibration the brain is part of
the universe the mental features are
part of the universe so this is the way
you will see next one I can't
deconstruct basically the brain so for
me and it's always a pleasure when I say
okay the mental thing is missing
especially the sun Dynamic is some slow
time scale longer time scale it always
puts you see a smile on my face uh
because it seems like you don't need to
think about something yeah and that's
what we called in this 2020 paper which
has taken up a lot fortunately uh comma
currents so there'll be explicate that
concept and I say this is what I call
spatial temporary so spatial temporary
Neuroscience it's not just okay there
are some topography and Dynamics in the
brain no that topography and Dynamics
shapes your cognition shapes your mental
state that special temperament
yeah that transition is an explicit
let's say if you want to say it's a
brain mind approach and you will see I
chose this for psychotic disorders I
indicate that for dreams and for mind
wandering we do this for self uh we have
the temple special Theory Of
Consciousness so it's all analysis runs
this morning I had a zoom with somebody
in my group for working normally there's
even the temporal envelope time scales
for working normally of course make
sense because it's a temporary phenomena
it's not a special cognitive
representation next one
so that's a shared special topography on
Temple Dynamic and now you will see
that's the way I deconstruct now mental
disorders so I always can see uh people
who discuss with me particularly the
mind one as the meditation I deconstruct
that in terms of spatial topography and
Temple Dynamic I infer happily uh back
and forth between phenomenal slash
experiential and neuronal level yeah we
had to see irreversibility so I look for
dynamic phenomenon maybe there's
something on the experiential side which
is often neglected but then I can also
ask my patients whether they experience
it and what there we go next one
so so that's basically here as I said to
indicated that what we developed this
Temple special Theory Of Consciousness
and first is really meaning spontaneous
and stimulus related activity because
that distinction is completely
artificial anyway the blowing if it were
sitting here it would smile how stupid
we are by using the brain
um and second it's an explicit link
between neuronal and phenomena
yeah uh I will I will give you later
some examples about meditation and
dreams as examples of that yeah very
short
next one
uh I already have that here next one
next one there must be another one yeah
so here okay I already give you the two
examples of the template spaces Theory
houses neuronal phenomenal linkage work
so this is meditation as a published uh
paper we published end of last year uh
so basically what we did it was done
here by the first also awesome Cooper
and Bianca Ventura
um we investigated uh naive versus
professional meditators FMI
and we looked for the whole written
pattern and one particular pattern was a
topographic pattern but here's a balance
between the Fortnight Network and
control executive Network usually they
stand in an anti-correlation negative
correlation uh so if the d1n is high the
c n is low and vice versa
and so that's basically the pattern was
found in naive meditators however now
when you go into uh profession so that's
basically in that organization goes
basically the cortical midline
structures DNM health Team often
associated with self-specific
self-related processing so it's an
internally oriented cognition whereas
the control executive network is an
externally oriented cognition it's goal
oriented so when I now look for you I
recruit more my control executive
Network whereas if I'm more sort of here
in myself and thinking in me undering
how could I make my talk better that
people understand me then it's more
internal oriented and cortical midline
structures so in that balance sort of
trips its neither so it's a beginning
it's like this and in the
intermediate stages like this and then
the professional meditators there's no
difference anymore it's neither a
positive or negative relationship
so and then also other data which I
don't present here we also see that the
relationship between DNA and
visual cortex is much more synchronized
the whole brain is much more unified
synchronized and less differentiated in
its topography so what does this mean
for input encoding your input is no
longer differentially encoded in the
different regions the input remains as
it is from the environmental
input and that's why you probably soon
colonize with the environment and that's
a basic experience of proficient
meditation you finally in tune with the
environment you hear this you have other
models you can have the the server who
is in synchrony in tune with the wave
the musician when you tap the beat to
the music your synchrony your brain
synchronizes and even I like that
particular you showed in recent paper
said if you have a certain Temple
structure in your task 20 to 30 seconds
you have a peak in exactly that
frequency range in your power Spectrum
kill the broom and caught the task
periodicity that's why I always wants a
temple structure of tusks it is often
neglected in completely neglected
it's much more clever than we think so
it's amazing so here in professional
meditators so what we said okay now you
have a dual organization internally
externally oriented cognition now on the
psychological level and that goes along
with the Dual organization of your brain
Dion and Versace
now in meditation you lose that dual
Topography of your brain and that's
exactly what you experience as
non-duality so that's a big thing that
you don't make here audio Duality self
other impinges upon your belief upon
your cognition but in the non-dual state
and it's very well described in the
middle letter which particularly when
you go to India they're crazy about
non-duality and non-locality this is
unbelievable uh so you really see that
Duality is no longer there and that no
longer shapes your thoughts your
environment so you don't make that
distinction
yeah
the basic subjectivity is preserved but
to serve nonsense dichotomy is no longer
there the basic subjectivity is
preserved your point of view as I would
say but I don't want to go into them so
and also interestingly see you'll see an
enlargement of your Dynamic repertoire
your Dynamic Lincoln had some nice
papers on that uh with the detained
fluctuation I notice you see you're
really see an enlargement of your
Dynamic variability and why is that
important the more variable your brain
the better you encode you can encode the
variable inputs from the environment and
that's so better you can align to the
stochastics of this movement I work here
if you have a large dynamic repertoire
you can follow me
yeah I hope so uh yeah
um and that's also you better align with
the environment but you process your end
you encode more inputs and you process
that input in a less differentiate way
so basically you less manipulate input
that's very well reflected in many
meditative experiences next one so
that's an example
where how
[Music]
the normal topography
translates into mental topography
[Music]
then that's you will see I make a
similar case now for mental disorders so
for me psychiatric disorders are
specific space-time disturbances and as
you know space and time have multiple
dimensions
so that's of course I can say now
they're spatial temporary disturbance
but that doesn't heal anything
clinically I need to specify and that's
what I will show you in the following so
for me mental disorders as a general
statement of space-time disturbance of
the brain's inner time in space maximum
I provide a little bit uh flesh to the
poems I'll show you two examples and the
first example is depression is a speed
disturbance next one so as you all know
depressing with melancholic the typical
there are different forms of depression
I don't want to get particularly I focus
here on the form of depression
where you sit in the corner you can't
get up in the morning you're depressed
you have rumination everything focus
upon yourself negative mood you don't
move your perceptionist and so on and so
forth so everyone
the working assumptions this is based on
on many years of studies and
phenomenology experience and back and
forth and Neuroscience in our show it's
really fast it's a speed disturbance
you're too slow your brain is too slow
and your psychological functions are
also too slow and your experience also
reflected slow now and that's a huge
this is for me basically when I speak of
a basic disturbance or generative
disturbance and one basically like the
relationship between glucose and insulin
is the generative disturbance for the
various diabetes symptoms throughout the
body
the null comparison I always like to
make that comparison so now comparison
in mental disorders only in depression
you have effective symptoms you have
cognitive symptoms you have sensory
systems you have motor symptoms you have
social symptoms
you have mind wondering problems you
have basically all cognitive functions
are changed
yeah and they're not as strongly change
let's say like in Dementia or like in
the frontal Dimension it's more sort of
a graceful degraduation there's some
computational it's even cross back I
think he used the term as a graceful
degradation of a network
yeah so so it's some sort of
subtle not clear stands highly
inter-individually variable symptom
constellation
so for me it's not a single symptom it's
a co-worker we call this co-occurrence
of symptoms
and how is that possible
so as I said that's in the same way as
in diabetes you have a co-occurrence of
symptoms here in the retina here in the
Victoria the gangreneur your symptoms
everywhere now imagine if you weren't
known
that this is related to insulin glucose
it would say these are all different
disorders
here are different people present you
would not combine them
yeah but once you know the basic
generative disturbance the glucose level
modulated by the insulin yeah makes
sense so glucose goes everywhere and so
on and so forth and the individual
difference
failure
so that's what I call so be careful when
I speak of generative or basic
disturbance I do not mean the cause
the causes of diabetes are the causes of
the depletion of insulin there are
multiple costs could be secondary or you
eat too many sweets environmental impact
yeah very interestingly I just want to
note that I come back yeah and it come
out to be by the heritable
type 1 diabetes and so forth I don't
know much about diabetes as you see okay
next one I just want to make the analogy
I'm not doing anything special or
metaphysically and next okay so now I
show you the slowness in different
domains psychological and brain so here
this is a line of research is visual
perception
so we do this motion suppression task
and it's intrinsically a dynamic task
because you have basically these little
uh gratings it's called they move and
you have to click the button when you
can see in which direction it moves so
the task itself is dynamic and what we
modified this is a standard task which
is very well known to a particularly
activate V5 middle Temple right higher
order visual cortex uh motion
suppression area so it's very well known
and you can calculate it through some
complex Circle physics uh which is too
high for me so you can basically and
reconstructed that how that perceives
this so this is this is a new Point what
we did because from these basically your
reaction time and other parameters and
how fast this move you can reconstruct
how much the gray level of these pixel
changes
yeah compared to the original and then
you can basically reconstruct how they
perceived the original and that's
important so this is what I call
subjective reconstruction because that's
what we need in Psychiatry how do people
subjectively perceive this thing your
objective measures are not relevant
because you want to see how that
perceives this thing so and then we also
included a fast and a slow version and
what we could see that the depressed
process perceives the fast version likes
a slow version so now imagine you cannot
make a difference between this
and between this what I did first was
the same as of course you become
depressed and you become detached
because you can't perceive half of the
reality so now I'm switching your
attention to this one yeah and where you
can reconstruct how much as I said the
grow level of the pixel changes relative
to the origin
and what you can see and you can
calculate that and curve if you called
chords is motion distance
and you can see that the difference
between the original
uh which is sort of somewhat somewhat
static uh is much larger in the uh
healthy so they're perceive it much more
dynamic
than the uh MDD so it's more static and
that's exactly when you ask the people
that's what they tell you yeah so it's
no longer they lose in their visual
cortex and when we showed that this is
related to decreased uh Power in the
faster frequencies in the exactly that
area in empty this is various papers we
published you see this over the last
next one
yeah this is for instance here so here
we did a separate uh experiments so here
we did uh
visual checkerboard stimulation in
different frequencies in four different
frequencies you can see this here on the
right we stimulated in four to eight
Hertz 1.2 Hertz 0.4 and 0 Hertz yeah so
to stick about same stimulus just
different frequencies so if we probe for
how the external dynamics of the input
modulates activity in particular here uh
here in the empty area and this was fmri
and you can see that in the healthy
subjects uh you have more higher
amplitudes of this glm modeling in FMI
higher amplitude in the two faster
frequencies no surprise because they
recruit more neurons more activity so
you have higher amplitude
the blue ones are the depression and you
can clearly see this here the depression
are less and then we grooved the two
slogans and the two fast run and you can
see a clear difference the depressed do
not process the fast ones in the empty
it's more similar to the slow ones so
one interestingly because this is really
a task it has been shown in monkeys and
animals and and humans this is really
empty but we also show that other
regions so
sorry
other reasons are strongly involved the
anterior cortical midline regions which
are known to be key in depression
so they're also involved and we can see
the same thing here there's no
difference how they process the Fast and
the slow stimula even where anterior
cortical Midland so that really suggests
Maybe
that's a whole brain thing and we have
another study which uh where we showed
different subjects are very short the
same thing next one
so
um then next one
so that's a therapeutic implications
because you can single out
patients who have particular Stone
visual perception
and V5 the normal difference
but we and marker and I want to use it
as such
so that's why we did one study oxygen
petal cortex TMS which in the field of
depression is unheard of because it's
everything does a lot of prefrontal
Cortex and maybe a little bit frontal
and if you do something else trust me
they kill you it's unbelievable because
there's a whole Mafia and there's money
involved and FDA approval private
practices and blah blah blah user
American way of doing things so and not
very good rates yeah 5066 reformers then
we did another study particularly for
motor cortex people and again we showed
very good efficacy so end of the story
probably doesn't matter where you apply
the TMS files because the brain acts as
a global brain next one you don't tell
that to the team Institute good so so
that's basically your show in input
regions is too slow on psychological and
neuronal levels that's why I'm so in the
modeling I really you see this in some
of the model stuff in our recent paper
for input encoding so I'm interested in
simulating different kinds of input
constellations and different kinds of
State dependencies how they relate to
different inputs because that's for Wiki
for me these disorders are encoding
yourself so now we did something really
interesting at least from my point of
view thoughts so what we did we try to
get into the thought Dynamics so this is
a line of research which we're doing
that we say we calculate that thoughts
in terms of time scales
and more will come out next one so here
we did a study where you can see this
here so subjects were in front of the
computer and they were instructed to run
the exact content change from internal
to external sort so external sorts
whenever there's a view environment
internal thoughts about my own self
and then they had to click the button
um and here we did it queue based you
can also do this non-q base uh and let
uh 10 20 30 and all in between uh second
where we gave cues how much it was
internally or externally oriented and we
also measured the degree of awareness
how aware are this thoughts we did this
in healthy uh depressed ndd major
depressive disorder and depressed
bipolar patient and the first thing
um maybe I show you next one
and after that next one
next one okay so now we did and we
reconstructed that in terms of the power
spectrum because you have a Time series
of change
yeah
and you can end your awareness ratings
so the awareness ratings are basically
uh uh
um yeah and here you can basically
calculate and you can reconstruct that
we didn't fft here and we construct that
time series and you have to do this for
quite some time so this was 15 minutes
because you need a number of Trials
obviously because you want to
reconstruct this so here's the frequency
and here is the power so it's the
frequency of your thought change
internal external Soul change and the
power associated with that
so you could see here it helps the
subject they have all frequencies
and a fair amount of power
Now look for the
ndd patients
no power
and not much change
ask the patients that's exactly what
they experience I'm drained off I have
no energy and nothing changes my thought
is the same ruminating thought circular
thought you see I indicated we correlate
that with a breathing as a subset of
rumination scale and exactly High
correlate now
in the depressed dipolar we saw a
similar pattern but not exactly the same
now you can go back
click
this one so here for instance I show you
one main result of that study that's a
frequency
of the sword was summed up slower in the
MDD than the duty so we have there are
similarities
between ndd and depressed bipolar which
of course makes sense but also some
difference
so another possible differential
diagnostic test
here which doesn't exist in the
literature next one now you can go ahead
ahead next one
so that's about sort
so
we're thinking there's one study of
course now you say do this for emotions
yeah so that's something of course we
still need to do but there's one study
in pns 2014 input at all from a Dutch
group it's very interesting they showed
indeed that the Dynamics before the
onset of depression you have a slowing
in your change in your emotions on the
psychological level
biblical dynamic system critical slowing
period yeah and that's exactly what you
observe and there's other paper since on
that so
I showed you some dynamic
and speed only
psychological and partial neurology
level nine I'll show you a little bit
about the topography
next one
so I'm a big fan of what is called the
global signal in FMI do I know guys
usually often money will just regress it
out however it has a physiological basis
has been shown in Monkey studies
combined electrophysiologically fmri
Leopold shermanik did some fantastic
papers there
and it's basically says there's an
infraslow fluctuations That's the
electrophysiological basis and what are
infraslow features that long cycle
durations they extend over several
regions so Global is to be understood in
a relative sense
yeah so we have big form of the global
signal
um I think there was a no no no no no
you're too fast for me and I'm too slow
for you okay there we are that's a
discrepancy
um so okay so what we did so now say
Okay more this is a uh remember what I
showed in the meditations these are
Global topographic new organization
disorders yeah your topography
reorganizes your balances we had one
paper in 2016 in pns where we showed
that the balance between DM and
intensive motor network is abnormal in
bipolar and differential cell in Mania
and depression yeah so here
um let me show you uh Global signal
pattern we replicated those findings and
others too that have increased Global
representation of brain activity in the
cortical midline structures instead of
forward mode Network
yeah and what do I mean by that so look
for climate change bad topic but
unfortunately very relevant you have a
global change in the ozone layer and
that is differentially Manifest in
different parts of the world
yeah that's exactly same with the brain
you have Global activity shared by all
regions of the brain but uh manifest to
different degrees in different regions
of the brain that's the global signal
topography calculated gscore
so in the two and depressions I show
significantly higher Global signal
activity here in the midline regions and
then investing the proof of principle
when you apply the global signal
regression then that difference appears
so that really suggests that there's too
much Global activity representation in
this Midland region everything is
focused on that
and the sensory regions remember the
visual cortex have decreased Global
signal representation so basically then
it was a very clever thing done by
Andreas calabrini a former postdoc of
mine who is now professor in Bergamo
um so then we correlated the GS in the
uh Department network was a non-defod
and you see an abnormal correlation
yeah that is uh when you apply uh the in
the healthy subject you don't see that
reading the fart mode and unimodal
regions are more independent in the
healthy subject
but in depression your unilateral
regions are completely enslaved by the
default mode your perception is enslaved
by your illuminations by your focus on
yourself you're negative your guilt and
everything that's exactly the clinical
reality then this was a small example 50
subjects
um we did machine learning we got an
accuracy of 90 with 50 subjects it's
nothing
you have studies with thousands and
hundreds that don't even reach coming
close
next one so clinically relevance next
one
okay now that's another diagnostic tool
which I would like to use it's a global
signal
representation so here I show your data
from uh that was a paper by Young head I
2017 in schizophrenia you see uh
abnormal conversion of your Global
signal representation between uni and
transmodal regions
then we saw them bipolar
increased Global signal representation
for among others in the motor cortex in
Mania that's very interesting because
when you see a manic patient she or he
walks around like crazy
so we have increased Global activity in
the motor coding that correlates with
your psychomotor agitation symptom yeah
in depression we got the hippocampus we
can see that here and again makes sense
increased normal ritual
autobiographical memory retriever yeah
and
next one yeah so I don't know just go
back
yeah and then the findings I showed you
before so you have three different
patterns of the global signal topography
in schizophrenia in bipolar in
depression clinical biomarker next one
so that's why we like to validate this
now in large-scale clinical studies so
same I showed you thoughts I showed you
visual perception I showed you brain now
I'll show you movements next one
um so here this is a paper just came out
last uh very end of last year so too
fast for me I'm depressed from your
perspective right
I didn't know that I looked like that
um so here we did a visual emotional
Paradigm it's a two by two uh fast
there's a slow and neutral versus
negative stimula because we monitor
interaction between speed of the
stimulus and the emotion so that's what
we did so in particular and we apply the
global signal stuff here so we did not
apply the usual
um uh uh amplitude based event related
blah blah blah approach but we've
applied a global signal approach so we
presented that in block a design four
blocks of these four conditions a
negative fast negative slow neutral slow
and fast
because for Global signal you need to
analyze in Block terms
so do you need a continuous data set and
maybe as somebody some water that's in
between I can drink a little bit sorry
um and so on what we observed here is
uh but in short uh Global signal
representation here in the uh different
regions and in depression
during the task particularly negative
fast they should decreased Global signal
representation
so they cannot activate the global
signal particularly in negative fast
similar and it was always a global
activity component when we did the GSR
Global signal regression the findings
disappeared as in the other paper so the
test is important of the global activity
component each region has two activity
components a global and the local
and that can shift and you see this
typical regions posterior cingulate
anterior midline regions here anterior
midline posterior singular typical
regions uh Superior Temple gyrus so like
typical depression regions and then
we did another analysis this is
apostolio just whole brain coronation
with psychomotor retardation because the
idea was maybe that correlates with the
degree of psychomotor retardation in our
scales
and there we are we got again of course
makes perfect sense we had the
pre-central gyrus primota cortex
inferior frontal gyrus posterior
cingulate cortex correlating with motor
retardation
so now given these findings you would
like to apply in subjects which show
strong cycle to retardation and Global
signal decreases in the motor cortex
that's the people who got should get
motor cortex DMS and we have one pilot
study which is we're just preparing for
submission where we successfully applied
TMs in motor cortex of depression so
here you have direct link of your
symptom potential potential mechanism
quote unquote
plus a therapeutic indication next one
so now you say okay uh how is all that
related to your negative emotions
so you want to know something wrong
again here topography next one
so and I have to make a little detour
here
um so the self is a big Topic in
Neuroscience uh there are probably as
many concepts of self as researchers
around and it's a catastrophe so here we
did the large scale motor analysis uh of
all task evoked studies on self on the
body on the interception and also on the
typical ah perfect that is very nice
thank you I appreciate it
um let me just have that and so here we
did a large scale meta-analysis or task
evoked studies
in
a healthy subject
and what we observed is sort of
so we looked for various regions
involved I don't go into details here
about that
um but we sort of observe based on the
data three different layers so
intersective regions typical insular I
don't mention that here salamos as a
subcortical regions because makes
perfect sense that's all the
interceptive tasks when we have
interceptive awareness uh original
heartbeat and all that when extraceptors
this was the proprioceptive task mainly
Ola blanca the studies an interesting
resource studies found the temple
periodical Junction you know all this
premoto cortex anti-metal prefrontal
cord but also replicated the same reason
as in The Intercept so these were
independent set of studies but these
regions which you observed here were
replicated here
yeah plus additional reasons among the
same these are the typical mental
self-task like trade adjectives or
autobiographical stories so it's about
your cognitive or mental self again you
saw to my delight of course also
according to commit line structure plus
the region from the previous level it
depends that so that hints Upon A nested
organization likes a Russian adult uh
um the shape of the smaller one is
replicated in the next larger one and so
forth yeah and you have also in China
you have beautiful Crystal Bots same
thing these are really beautiful it's
incredible yeah so you have a nested
organization now what do you think this
nested organization
when some of this balance changes that's
what happens in psychotic disorders next
one now you're allowed to click
okay perfect so now you need it so here
we did again it's an FMI
it's an FMI approach again this Global
signal so we looked for the degree of
global activity representation in
stop
[Music]
this is tricky I don't know why that is
okay
um some hidden artificial intelligence
there
um so so we basically investigate the
degree of global signal representation
in these different regions of the
different layers of cells in healthy and
in depression
and this is FMI
and what we observed and during the task
during an emotional attention task and
you could again see inter as okay X
receptive and these were trait
depressions these were non-acute MDD
patients so this is trade features it's
important it's non-acute and what you
could see it's an increase in the X
receptive and also an increase in
dementia no surprise that goes well with
the symptoms
and here we uh it's the same for the
different we plotted this is the same
data plotted here but according just the
sequence the balance between the three
different layers and you see it's really
very much different there's still these
two layers Stand Out compared to the
intercept
so you see already that the growing
signal represent in Roma I present
overall Topography of DM and non-dmn now
I present you within
basically the transmodal regions I again
show you an altered topography with an
abnormal increase in the dmn and that's
related to yourself stuff then we also
did an emotional attention task
um and the behavioral data of that I
don't want to go into this this is the
multinomial regression analysis so we
had four values of the emotional
attention task whether they could attend
it or not positive negative and neutral
and you could see that these different
layers also modulated the emotional
attention task and so meaning
you have an abnormal Global signal
representation across the three layers
of cells and that in turn leads to other
normal emotion regulation or
dysregulation or emotional attention so
here you see that the self might be on a
psychological level disturbance because
it's in Boston and everything
so again these three layers that's what
I want to develop it's probably
hopefully a differential diagnostic
marker for instance in anxiety disorders
you see a decrease there
okay okay so that's difficult then I
speed up okay I finished the depression
in time and then I um next one
next one
next one you already know this
okay next one no go back
so many more slides coming
okay I hope you'll be taking a couple of
more minutes
okay good
um so here you can say yes but maybe
your time changes your speed change it's
just a consequence of abnormal cognition
that's the way cognitive people would
argue for
and I said no
even on the psychological level your
abnormal time in the brain
constitutes or generates an abnormal
time perception of slowness and that in
turn shapes your cognitive function in
an abnormal way and slash your symptoms
so it's an abnormal Dynamic scaffold or
envelope for cognitive functions
so and yeah people would argue in a
psychiatric process it's a Time
perspective time perception is just a
consequence of the depressive symptoms
as I said I said the other way around so
here we tested this
pure psychological study 100 subject and
I know I need to be fast so we also
investigated childhood trauma
higher incidence in these depressed
patients and we are two different
mediation models easier time perspective
zimbardo Intel perspective interval uh
inventory either is a moderator or is a
dependent variable so which model
mediation model hold this one this
yielded a full mediation
this one not so if you have a trauma you
might
try or might not lead to depression of
your time perspective your time
perception is normal
yeah and here
this is the other way around this year
the full mediation no mediation at all
so this really support for me time
perspective next one
okay and we have another line of
research again with my former post
talking there will be a few different
layers of trauma related to the three
layers of self does this goes strong on
the psychodynamics this is a
collaborator here because she in from a
purely psychodynamic perspective
distinguish these three levels of trauma
but I don't have time next one
good I hope that's clear and I hope I
could also indicate it has potential
biomarker relevant next one so now this
I will walk you very quickly through uh
temple in Precision next one
uh positive negative symptoms so the
idea is here this is a temple in
Precision you're imprecise next one I
show you the data and I walk through so
fast uh Timber windows are too long next
one
so here we did also the next one uh we
no no no stop uh we did also the uh
autocorrelation window and we probe for
temple integration if you integrate too
much you're temporally imprecise yeah
um so we prove for temporal integration
on the marijuana level measuring the
autocorrelation window uh and on the
psychological level by this continuous
task is a phase morphing task from the
zakira's originally uh face more often
task where you have to indicate when
it's no longer your face or when it's
your face so itself as a self morphing
and in either direction you go and
that's basically temporary integration
because if you integrate too much you
still see another person's face as your
own face so that's a design because it's
Temple integration which is in the
Paradigm itself next one
yeah that's the autocorrelation window
uh basically you measure your time
series with itself the decrease to which
it correlates in terms of next next one
uh yeah so here next one uh we saw that
the autocorrelation window is too long
in the schizophrenic patients and that
is that was 2021 published you see this
here significantly longer here the red
ones compared to the blue ones and this
is replicated in a completely
independent data set which was just
published a couple of months ago you
again see the autocorrelation window
doing the Oddball task and in the
resting state too long so your two long
Windows you integrate too much so we can
temporally imprecise next one yeah I'm
temporally imprecise now I know but I
try to uh judge so how is that related
to symptoms so here we were lucky we
could collaborate here with Carlos and
Denmark who developed this unfortunately
David is not here David Martinez I I'm
sure he knows his scale for uh
experience of their own self abnormal
itself and that's a qualitative
interview and what we could see that the
relationship between the basic selfless
order and schizophrenia and negative
symptoms is mediated by your time scale
so that is beautiful because you see
during your own operates in the
background and mediates the transition
to the single that's exactly what I want
that's why I speak of space or Temple
psychothergy next one
okay next one I probably skipped yeah
okay next one I next is very short so if
you confuse internal and external
reality then how's that related on the
mironal side meaning you may not be able
to make a proper distinction between
your resting state or pre-stimulus
activity and your task evoked activity
moving your external task or input is
not properly differentiated from your
ongoing activity so my ex you you look
at me but I just don't process that
really properly just integrate it into
my ongoing mentation my inner thought
and of course then I think you will want
to kill me or some strange stuff yeah so
that's exactly so here we did the
meta-analysis on different EEG that is
mainly on also fmr and schizophrenia
those studies which included both rest
or pre-similar's activity and task
revoked activity in the analysis and you
will see it's not many studies this was
truly 21. so catastrophe and reviewers
ask me why are you doing this is not
relevant it's incredible yeah so he
showed this and whether the pre-stimulus
measure is high or low his red stuff is
too low or too high different kinds of
EEG measures in each case you have
decreased three stimulus task difference
so that's really here system is an
extreme Dynamic State too high or too
low it doesn't react anymore
next one
and that's of course confusing the
internal extern next one so this is a
really interesting stuff you know I have
to drink a little bit I hope that Melody
will give me and then I continue here so
here we look now
for Temple and Precision in the
millisecond range
in the amplitude
and in the face of the EEG signal
so this here this was very dangerous was
done by her from Greece
I never can pronounce her name so it's
Maria is her first name it's easier for
me so and she applied his very clever
approach uh it was an internal
initiation Paradigm where you're based
as you click and then you get a tone
uh and she applied a temple transfer
function is a very clever that and what
you could see that could see in all
these frequencies EEG obviously that you
could see increased delays in the
amplitude by applying this transfer
function yeah and she also saw a
increased intra-subject variability of
those stimulus so that's the amplitude
uh is uh modulated and more unstably
delayed into schizophrenic and this is
millisecond yeah so that's you could
find out through the transfer function
and again replicated
so then we did for the face so in the
amplitude you have some Temple and
Precision in the millisecondary now
interface this is intertrial Phase
coherence you have an auditory Oddball
Paradigm continuous tones you have to
click the button but you have to pick
the button only when there is a deviant
so it's called an attention Paradigm but
for me it's an external synchronization
pattern where you have to synchronize
and you can see the phase onsets
synchronize with the onset of the
external stimulus the line
so what you see in the trifex coherence
in the healthy subject you see in
particular inseta and Delta because
that's the reason of the inter-trial
interval of your tones nobody is
mentioning that you see that a high
phase coherence in the brain and you see
the c as a typical phase Circle High now
in schizophrenia you don't see that
the phase can't synchronize and who sees
this when you have music therapy with
depression they stand around the
schizophrenia don't know what to do
yeah because they cannot synchronize
because it's temporally imprecise this
is here and this is one of the best
replicated findings the decreased phase
coherence and we combine that also with
computer computer computational modeling
to see it's really the phase offsets
but this is diagnostic specific you
don't see this in bipolar on depression
we have a paper in revision and
molecular Psychiatry on the next one
I know I'm almost over so here now you
say how is your face coherence the
millisecond related to the more longer
time scale of the uh autocorrelation
ring so this is uh again now with this
here we could replicate there's another
data set replicate the autocorrelation
window could replicate the decreased in
the trial phase coherent now how are
they Linked In The Healthy subject the
black line they highly correlate yeah if
you have shorter autocorrelation window
you have higher inter trial phase cohere
because you're not tempted if you have a
shorter window temperature segregation
you're more totally precise interface
onset to follow these thoughts and my
speech hopefully and in the depression
that doesn't exist anymore moving your
ACW you tender window provides a
template
for your synchronization yeah and that
is lost and the schizophrenic patients
are literally lost and this is
millisecond range next one
um so then you say where is this coming
from these are all task data now showing
you whether there's some face
inconsistencies in the resting state how
do you measure that so Stephanie very
clear guy from Austria he developed a
new method a very small band pass five
to seven Hertz and you basically
calculated the projected cycled time
point of the cycle durations of the
ongoing secretary and then you can you
can measure the how the Deviant so the
spontaneous face variability and that
spent on his face variability is too
entropic in the schizophrenic patient
irregular in preside milliseconds yeah
this is really many seconds
yeah so this is really and you see it's
too high entropy here applied in central
entropy on this spontaneous phase
variation
next one we do this more and more also
on behavioral data second order analysis
of the times next one okay so then close
to the end
how is that manifest and subjective
experience
so we developed a spice and time
experience scale for schizophrenia and
we also now we have in the loop in our
pipeline this uh time and space
experience scale for depression and
anxiety because I want to map this also
again differential diagnosis and certain
items here particular item number seven
so this is a schizophrenic group this is
the
non-schizophrenic bipolar effective
group and this is healthy subject you
see item seven is almost specific for
every patient experience of temporal
fragmentation yeah and premium Mission
also he has a premonitional typical item
made yeah so that's it's also one of the
diagnostic layers which can be used and
again same for time space experience and
depression next one
so next one okay I probably skip that
one even we did some drawing on those
guys and see again temporally fragmented
you see Temple fragmentations everywhere
for me next one except in my own brain
of course
um there's no time at all so temporary
Precision next one
clear I hope it's entertaining I think
it's a revolved for stock of mine uh
who's now professor in Queens has this
very nice uh
heading next one and that also goes with
some old phenomenology in in
schizophrenia minkowsky uh very clever
guys psychiatrist he described it as a
loss of vital contact with reality now
you see I added the dynamic and that's a
temple in Precision if you cannot
synchronize cannot encode the inputs in
millisecond range you're confused and
that carried faster the rest of your
break next one so for me it's an
encoding that is it okay next one
um so here I show you that basically I
think I hope I made a clear common
currency or we missed an end there uh
common currency of brain and symptoms we
have different lines which you can
diagnose next one
uh here uh we have subjective experience
which I would like to include then you
have these different markers which I
showed you special measures template
measures which I think yield strong
support that there might be a sort of
what you say diagnosis of syndrome
specificity and that really awaits
larger clinical trials next one
the next one uh I next one I indicated
that it is Major implications for
therapy particularly in depression I
showed you the TMS stuff individual
cortex motor cortex and also we have
currently an ongoing study in anxiety
where we use a breathing protocol and
why the reason because anxiety a fast
and irregular breathing thoughts are
racing like crazy so they have temporal
irregularity and that yields Temple
uncertainty and if there's uncertainty
too much you become afraid so there's a
lot of some computational study for
temple uncertainty for uncertainty but
it's not really associated with a
dynamic or Temple uncertainty that's the
way I add so it's the next to what they
investigate on the cognitive level so
while breathing because I'm bruising
long if you breathe very slow
you have long face Cycles they're good
for integrating your different thoughts
and your different stimuli and calm you
down
and we see dramatic effect so this is a
tentative this is 10 subjects you see
this is a back anxiety scale and this is
a mind-wandering scale spontaneous mind
wondering you see a reduction this is
after three weeks after six weeks you
see a huge reduction in T1 T2 and
important in all subjects all of the 10
Single subjects showed a big anxiety
reduction
that's unheard of in Psychiatry okay
it's pilot data it's early but that's
again one of the tools besides the DMS
for a large stay clinic right and we
also individualize the breathing
frequency uh with lots of time we let
them breathe some different frequency
ranges from let's say breathing rates
from five to uh to 12 or 14. and see
which and then we have various like at
scale and which one is the most
comfortable breathing rate for them so
we individualized and we later want to
do this with the EEG and also with a
computational modeling next one
yeah and I come to the end uh last talk
I probably overstepped my 10 minutes uh
yeah and if you want to read this is
about a lot of psychiatric case
histories is the most recent one both
books are very short and I think well
understandable thank you very much
thank you thank you so much you're very
inspiring talk
um we will have a time for overall
discussion so in
uh I think that we can
start with our next speaker that is
cloud there and we will have I have a
plenty of questions for you uh but we
will have a full time for discussion at
the end of the presenters thank you so
much
hey
super good
um
yes yes
representative
okay
you were not that lucky I'm sorry
you were not that lucky you know
thank you
um biological
[Music]
um
nothing
is
Elementary
El cambia
um presentations
estatica
a year
compartment
is
instruments
definition
is
[Music]
Etc
um
promoters
[Music]
and foreign
publication
foreign
[Music]
La Masa
inflammatory
um
negrita
is
immunological
presentation
distance
[Music]
foreign
disturbances
Etc
um
[Music]
foreign
parallel
the physical
una correlation a positive
trabajo
boys
[Music]
America
foreign
relations
adults
um
Americans
reviews
Pacific
ocean
um
the regulations
foreign
[Music]
resistance
in English
foreign
the Lord
um
mindfulness yeah
um processes
the
um
persona
cerebral
[Music]
yes
um
mental
Chronicle
inflammatory
thank you Ontario
is
emotions
investigator
procedure
foreign
destiny
is
mindfulness basis
anxiety disorders
foreign
um
incentives
Highlander
is modifications
foreign
automatically
um
Pennsylvania
regulations
foreign
Connecticut
um
foreign
thank you
resolution
[Music]
foreign
representations
[Music]
beneficials
foreign
[Music]
you know foreign
activities
[Music]
meeting
discussions
foreign
[Music]
these foreign aspects from mental health
in different mechanisms of you know
brain cells that we are really really
looking forward to and Mario make a
great presentation about digital
condition and this challenge that we
Metallica so now we have a copy you can
grab a coffee there five minutes
something and then back here and
bringing all your ideas to discuss we
will do it in English yes for for having
yours on board in the discussion but if
you don't speak English you can
mentioned okay
thank you
foreign
[Music]
um
foreign
[Music]
analysis
thank you
I don't know
opportunity
[Music]
um
videos
[Music]
thank you
again
[Music]
very much
um
everything
else
thank you
important
yes
services
thank you
foreign
this evening
[Music]
anymore
um
thank you
so I guess we'll do a brief introduction
so if you can see across the different
presentations we are talking about a
very
um old-fashioned distinction what is
physical world what is mine or what is
you know
um causal explanations versus other
explanations and this reminds me in the
specifically in the in the field of
mental health this kind of decision you
know the system between those both
Fields they have tremendous effects you
know in lateral red syndrome it was a
condition that was jumping from
Psychiatric to neurological disorder so
it was a genetic conditions versus was a
repressive masturbation by currency
psychoanalytic theory they come back
again and was confused with Huntington
disease there is another disease and
this is just because
we don't have good models to understand
the similarities the same way that yours
is you know connecting Brian and means
we can do in psychiatric and
neurological conditions or in mental
health in general we know a lot about
from
influences exposome external influence
lifestyle choices to
internal mechanism mechanistic Pathways
inflammatory endocrine immune microbiome
Etc but also we know that we have tools
theoretical tools that can integrate can
be dimensionally applied between the
both sides and also interventions that
can be applied between both sides so
it's a it's a great start I have a
question for George one in Israeli and
so I just want you to bring your voices
uh and it's a huge opportunity for make
questions for the speaker but also for
provide your own insights so I I will
open the discussion right now
if there are no question I will start
with George uh can you talk a little
with how your approach can be extended
to neurology I mean we have been working
together I'm pretty sure you have some
ideas just to
to bring this discussion about you know
psychiatric and neurological conditions
yeah first and foremost of course you
have depression and anxiety in your
patients too from the temporary dementia
Alzheimer's dementia minimal cognitive
impairment probably maybe even in the
subject of cognitive impairment which
would be an interesting candidate
um so definitely I would screen the
literature for that and that's of course
should be it's a syndrome
um so that would be I think the most
direct link and probably many of these
symptoms lead you to the doctors maybe
even before the memory complaint
and the second thing of course then I
would need to go into some of the memory
um
complaints they have
and for me it would be very interesting
the earlier subjective
impairment and minimal cognitive
impairments
and then I would put look for those
memories
in Dynamic terms so what does this mean
I would for instance we have a study now
where we analyze working memory and
dynamic terms and I would do the same
here and maybe particularly in these
early stages
uh I could imagine the memory function
itself is intact but you have some
Dynamic changes and I know that the
group by Macintosh former Toronto now in
Vancouver they did some of this
variability and dynamic stuff in early
agent and you see changes yeah you slow
down maybe uh that I could imagine so I
would look for that and then you can
apply the same kind of matters
which I have in particular with the
cognitive memory Paradigm I just want to
mention that Mario has been developing
this binding working memory task versus
future integration that dividends
requires integration of future I mean
color and and the form of the stimuli we
have a lot of data including easy and
fmri so we can apply your spatial
temporal so the idea hypothesis we will
have longer time window for binding in
comparison to Future
yeah yeah I would
is a classical working memory task with
you know studio and set so we have this
this long period to calculate the ACW
and yeah so show me the exact Temple
structure of the Paradigm I look at the
temple structure of the Paradigm because
cognitive people neglect that that's an
intertrial interval interstimulus
intervals I'm very keen on this and then
I can tell you how to analyze and what I
would expect fantastic right
any question please first
thank you
so a really nice part I was wondering
whether you have blood or other people
have thought about
integrating body signals into the
general
slow foreign
yeah good question
um you are absolutely right so of course
I would argue in our sixth paperless
every postulate that and that's the AC
autocorrelations and you're strongly
involved in input encoding so here
really focus on the encoding not the
decoding which is an important
difference and they'll need to tell you
that one and of course the encoding is
not only the external input it also the
continuous internal input internal input
from the body and internal input
probably from strong variability changes
within the brain itself
because they might be treated like an
input like spindles in the case of sleep
and one and two sleep it's like a strong
internally generated input Thalamus
cortical variability change
and of course I would argue that they uh
processed by the end encoded
by the same temporal mechanism of
external impulse so meaning I know I
made a little detour of course I would
argue and we already discussed this in
one study link fund particularly the
autocorrelation window to the uh
heartbeat evoke potential and I know
that there is one study for instance for
scale free activity it's a parallel
exponent and of course you see
responsibility to the Apple so it's
clear because it's a scale free system
yeah and of course the brain will react
and that's for me con so if you want to
put it in a larger perspective with
complexity magic Bruce West
a comment on that and connecting with
allostatic over lower now after hearing
you several times but after this visit I
understand the relevance of encoding in
your approach right so the the inputs
this is so because it's a
it's not the typical way that the people
interpret the inputs and when we think
in allostasis you know it's supposedly
the responses to environmental demands
but those responses depend your internal
organs your Dynamics your internal
Dynamics your encoding of this external
information so I see
better links as our paper are really
submitted to connect allostasis with
this internal time scales like you know
the internal structure not only to
respond to environmental environmental
demand but to explain the term anything
you know because same stressors can
trigger different internal States or
even exposure you know you can you can
understand the explosion like external
trigger but you have a lot of internal
signals you know that accessor beta
explosion so if you want to I mean
imagine you have a lot of money and you
can you can do you can measure wherever
you want what should you
pick up choose for for an allostatic
interest analostatic index sorry
yeah
um
is an easy good question is the
expectation question the the use of
biomarkers in assignment I mean if I
have a lot of money a lot of funding I'm
going to use several I mean most of the
most of them the the the the the primary
ones the
I mean all of them because all of them
are related that I can't find we can
find them the distance type of uh
allostatic index wait wait because maybe
I was I was saying too much imagine you
don't have all the money so you have to
pick up three of them what should be the
best
yes
[Laughter]
yeah I know how to what
can I use um
the first one is
the second one
um
something
how to say
cheaper this is a how to say
um
wait wait yeah and the third one is the
moon inflammatory proteins directive
protein
thank you so much
for your questions please please
[Music]
because we have guests online
okay uh when I when I when I started
your presentation let's talk about this
speech uh uh brain modulation and people
with depression I I thought well this
might probably be change so how about
then you show that you have used TMS uh
to kind of restore uh or try to so then
and I was wondering if you have thought
or whether it would be feasible to use
biofeedback some form of biofeedback uh
in this in this patient with depression
to kind of speed up like the entrainment
maybe or what are you thinking about
well I think in EEG based by a new
configuration by your paper because you
show the frequency changes as a
byproduct of depression and that's why
they tend to process things lonely and
so on and so forth so then if we feel
this information bad biologically and
there are many ways to do that now could
it be possible to kind of
help them bring them back to track in
terms of speech at the neural level and
therefore hopefully at the clinical
behavioral level as well
yeah I mean that's exactly the idea so
in uh that's what I would do if I would
individualize so we individualize the
region uh now I'm really looking forward
to a large clinical study and there I
need what you just promised a lot of
money or facilities
um and I cannot do this academically
yeah
um that you really have say okay you
have uh three arms study you have either
motor cortex visual cortex or
dozolateral prefrontal cortex according
to the neuronal and psychological
deficit so you have a working memory
task following the dialogue letter you
have a motor cortex task which I didn't
show you a motor tapping Precision error
which we can do
uh this is established and we have the
psychological visual tasks as I showed
and then the next thing you want to do
EG and fmri and Method Dynamics into a
power spectrum of those respected
regions okay and compare that also with
the behavioral data so you do a Power
spectrum of the behavioral data two for
instance of the finger tapping how much
they're lacking behind
and then you have basically the power
Spectrum on the behavior level as well
as on the EEG and on the fmiser interest
loan range and then you get sort of an
overview of different time scales and
see how much are they relate with each
other you can do Mutual information you
can do a vector Auto regressive uh model
for linking these different time series
and then you see how they are linked to
each other so that gives you sort of a
fingerprint of the neurodynamic basis of
their behavior and I'm insisting here on
the behavior because so much in therapy
goes either pure on the psychology or
pure on the neuronal and that's Nick and
I would like to even include my
subjective experience skills I'm after
all a phenomenologist as a philosopher
where I'm coming so also this depression
which I didn't show you the time space
experience scale of depression so if I
have that and then I have the data to go
into computational model so then ideally
you clever guys you converge my EG data
my individual EEG with the computational
remember that the two red points dots we
were discussing yeah so then you can
simulate how I can change that
particular
neuronal Dynamics PSD or whatever or the
correlation Windows scale and of course
you probably also want to have a dynamic
autocorrelation window which I didn't
show here
which you need to have
and then how I can change it how I need
to tune the computational system to
change that frequency and that way we
again for each subject differently which
I suppose depends also on the dynamic
repertoires that's the variability which
that's why I wanted Dynamic acid and I
think that's bringing the biofiber to a
modern level and then he can give me the
exact data and then I come to you and I
don't know you seem to be a social
scientist but maybe you can build me the
right machine where I can Implement that
within continuous online feedback system
so I start with the frequency which he
recommends me the Red Dot how we can
shift it yeah and then we can build this
yeah but I would not do this before
because now the current data on BCI and
TMS are at best
individuals
towards personalization
because you really have the holistic
approach the AGP you're not just a
biological the psychological or the
environment
so what I can do this could be run in a
larger clinical studies either the TMS
this is 3M TMS end with the computation
model or for the breezing the breezing
might be a slightly easier thing uh the
only thing in the model then is how do
you apply a breathing pile to the model
that's not an easy one because the input
is the real problem of the formalization
of the input on your side yeah we
discuss this in our group we have no
solution to that oh because you just you
do yeah yeah so that's sort of no I
think we need to make a discussion
between breath and mindfulness but first
Carol have a question
thank you
um so can you hear me no
yes okay yeah
um so I have two questions for two
speakers so I will start with York
um so you started your your
um discussion your presentation saying
that models uh addressing genetics and
disease are not enough so
um so you said in your presentation that
models uh use in genetics and disease
those kind of models are not enough
I'm wondering if we are missing some
parts so um since my I have a background
in epigenetics I'm wondering uh well
these epigenetic changes have risen as a
mechanism connecting
um genetics of a person and experiences
environmental stimuli so I'm wondering
whether you think that maybe genetic
regulation through epigenetics can add
something to the topic
it was against the case number okay the
case numbers are not substitute
and I used falsely now genetics as an
example okay anyway so first of foremost
I'm not an expert in genetic epigenetics
I cannot say much so this is so
everything I say it just comes from a
very bird's eye view from somebody who
has no expertise in them
um but just say coming from my clinical
side now I speak as a psychiatrist
what is clear
life events play a key role in that
in different ways first they triggers
basically all depressive patients
therefore and it's not the objective
language
it's a subjectively perception of that
life
two different two Claudia and I two
different people same life events
exactly the same life even I become
depressed she remains no okay so don't
tell me why that is so and that's a
problem because that depends and that's
why I would argue remember this one
slide where I had the childhood trauma
in the time perception
that's the thing yeah so and that I
think and then that's a trigger in that
but then you have also more
concentrative life
uh trauma continues trauma you become
depressed or you react with the PTSD or
post-traumatic stresses or whatever
and of course epigenetic changes like
absolutely clear though that's what so
far I can go I cannot go further because
I'm lacking the expertise I can
compliment a little bit on that up sorry
so first of all
um I think that we have a bias with
genetics we tend to immediately forget
that the genes need
expression and genus genes are inside an
organisms you know this is so important
and what you start to thinking about in
more complex genetics right like cmbs or
for PRS polygeometrics score right the
interaction with environment is critical
and when we talk about epigenetics oh my
God you should be interested in that
because one important thing is
epigenetic looks is Dynamics is is again
temporal Dynamics and how the burden
across all the lifespan modulate this
clock interact interacting with the
genetic and depressed position so as you
know we need more of this kind of
dialogue you know because um
in red light we do a lot of genetics and
it's incredible they huge opportunities
we miss to connect the dots from
environmental factors to genetics and
then to this important aspect of
subjective experience right
we need to change that dialogue if you
can provide time scales with enough data
points yeah I mean I'm talking at least
100 data points if not more then we can
do the same measures
yeah yeah like autocorrelation we know
one of my favorite as you probably
figured but also other sample entropy
what we did in this case exactly as you
could do because after all the different
levels must communicate with each other
because my assumption is that's tempting
so it's the encoding process between
brain environment is Temple then I'm I'm
it's a reasonable assumption that maybe
the encoding process from the inner of
the organism and the different layers is
also done yeah I make a very strong
claim imagine
but then meaning we could link and the
ultimate is that should be scale free
organization so the same kind of pattern
which you see in your dynamics of your
epigenetics I should somewhat see
similar pattern in my smaller time
scales of my brain time so that would be
great exactly yeah that's okay free so
you provide a large Russian doll I just
have a small one compared to New York
Times maybe but I don't know but this
can bring you know special temporal
Dynamics beyond the brain because yeah
temporal metrics of different organs
modulated by the epigenetic Rocks but
it's a temporal code exactly connected
it's a temporary coding process that's
why I'm kidding yeah English is our
common code now it's the only one I
don't speak Spanish yeah uh so there we
are yeah if you don't that's like the
temple quote in the brain for me with
the brain body environment so the
principal difference I'm sure that the
brain you know I always think brain sits
here and listens to us and says how
stupid are you to separate me from the
body and the environment it's just one
thing for me it's just a matter of
balances it's continual and that's
what's a patients
yeah second question yeah I have another
question poor Constance at this time
um so I was
seeing your presentation with great
interest and you mentioned some
different effects of a mindfulness on
different biomarkers current metabolic
by markers stressed by markers Etc yes
um so I'm wondering whether there's
maybe some study you have read maybe you
you are familiar with since you have a
background in Biochemistry
um have you seen any study reporting any
gene expression changes uh related to
mindfulness
Okay so
I don't know if I think
okay great thanks
so
the exactly mechanism how this happened
I mean the the most close we are is that
we have some pattern of activity in the
brain that for instance you encode for
something that is kind of very real or
not real and there is done in going
there and that information
uh goes down through the hippo AKA
totalom hypothesis axis and you generate
uh
um you know a solution of different
hormones and that's it so that is kind
of how the things happen and then you
have the cortisol that Claudia explained
to adrenal
how this happened with dims is not very
clear there are
um genetic epigenetics modulations but
not I mean is to the level of gene
expression but not Gene like
modification of course and uh and this
is related to the measurements is more
that have been targeted is in Pro
cytokine inflammatory expression and
interlockings uh also and
um yeah kind of this range of like
pro-inflammatory
environments in a way and this is true
uh yeah mutilations and and this is the
mechanisms methylation so yes
but exactly how that is orchested
uh is is not really very clear
um because also there is some
confoundings in I must say and disclaim
in meditation studies
especially with the advanced meditator
studies where a lot of these foundings
that has to do with the lifestyles that
you begin to have when you engage in
meditative or complaint contemplative
practice like
um the degree of awareness of your
elementation and like bodily awareness
making sport or not that that also
generate like an holistic change through
pro-inflammatory I mean decreasing this
pro-inflammatory environment or
stressful Lifestyles that we could have
so there are some
um short-term studies with eight weeks
showing already epigenetic change
and also in telomerase is the minimum
time for expression
but normally the the biggest effect is
for more for longer time and then you
begin to have a confounding with
lifestyles in general
um so yeah one more little thing uh I'm
curious for myself uh is there any like
type of person that is more prone to
meditate like easily to be like Advanced
meditators is there any praise position
or some some time or some type of person
that meditation comes easily for them
um
that I really I I'm not sure of I mean
there are some studies about relating
the week five with like because you have
like some like great mindful
um
um outcomes you know you have like State
mindful or trade there are people that
is normal more mindful like if you may
if you pass to people in this room the
mindful scale mindfulness scales there
are more people even though they don't
meditate that they're going to have a
more uh like mindful trait yeah but
people that normally approach to to to
to to meditate is people that is
normally more anxious and have normally
more prompt to be anxious or to be
stressed and people look for meditation
when they are in uh not very good mental
health shape which is natural it's like
looking for medicine but in a way of
practice in a way so I would say that
people that approach to meditate for
mental health reason normally is a
select group of anxious people
and but then this has his his
consequences of course and
um but there is there is people that is
more disattached or that have less
cognitive Fusion that is more like
mindful as a trait in a Continuum but I
don't know if for these people it's more
easy to meditate because always there is
some I mean there are obstacles for each
type of people right so there are people
that it's going to have some fights with
their like solidification of thoughts
and there are people that have a profile
that is more evitative so it's his
evitative patterns of thinking are the
the obstacles for them when they come
from their meditation so
so as you may know this question that
Carol has made is very important because
probably you are very aware about this I
see this nature communication or nature
of human behavior paper showing that the
effect of mindfulness are not such as
strong as we believe
and there are a lot of failure so but
the question is personalized medicine so
what's the degree of of mindfulness or
breathing or you know if we are thinking
about mechanisms for self-regulation
perhaps that is one of the mechanism
associated with mindfulness or producing
allostasis right why we don't think in
multi-component interventions in in the
field of brain health the
multi-component interventions are the
best no comparison with any other across
all all possible interventions so maybe
exercise breathing and mindfulness
combining and personalized right so
maybe you want to mention your how you
you know personalize the assessment of
of breathing so we can but first let's
start with your opinion about this yes
sure so we we publish a paper last year
actually how meaningfulness-based
intervention were difficult different
brilliantly differently and uh efficient
for different type of
mindfulness based Baseline people so
um for sure there is there is a thing of
uh baselines where people arrive with uh
and also there is a timing that is very
important for instance for the things
that I show for depression it's not when
you have the person in the more acute
episode of depression but is when they
are really for relapsing and so I think
is very important what you mentioned
because actually what you are fostering
is a kind of a mental culture of
um not going to the doctor in a way when
you are like completely done and when
they okay great sure
um and so so you are fostering kind of a
more preventive a moralistic approach so
you go you can turn whatever you need to
do more exercise or or have a better
element station or if you are like not
sleeping too much because you need to do
this you need to then you kind of
counterbalance meditating or whatever so
yeah hopefully we arrive to something
like that but to prevent like Dementia
or all these things normally you have to
to try to sustain the better lifestyle
uh you could do whatever so maybe it's
useful to do some kind of it will be
very
accident but to look kind of a lifestyle
index com like that you could okay that
you can kind of put there your credits
on meditation and running and stuff and
and to see like basically how much
drinks you're gonna have in the weekend
without like you know compensating your
oxidative kind of yeah
[Music]
um
interesting comments I mean
first off sir I think one thing which is
really neglected in the meditation
literature is the induction method and
the data on the neuronal side extremely
heterogeneous because you have all kinds
of induction methods I was in India last
year invited
and
um I mean you can't imagine what kind of
breathing techniques they have through
the nostrils different nostrils and it
is insane
and of course when you're there you have
to undergo all of that because it's only
experience counts lots of knowledge it's
incredible so anyway so I think that's a
key thing so different people prefer
different induction methods
um that's of course and I would argue
the meditative state is a common final
function of the password I know that
some review of our papers killed that
figure we had a nice figure different
induction they all lead to non-duality
and I would keep the induction
techniques in a very wide sense for me
for instance I'm a runner so I like run
and women in nature that's like a
meditative state from a flow statement
so I would Define it very well so
meaning that's where you need to
individualize and now we actually
investigated where one paper in
preparation where we really look for the
different kinds of induction techniques
how they because that's input encoding
it's an internal input which you encode
the breathing input oil mental input how
that relates of course to my beloved
measure of ACW and one of the reasons
why I'm so focused on this ACW is also
pragmatic reason we have other measures
parallel exponents in they don't yield
in those context they don't yield those
results
for other yes you would see this in
order
so that's internal input encoding that
leads back to the question which you
raised for the heartbeat and the
intrinsic neural time scale yeah so also
the internal input is in code so now I
would then basically let's say again I
would do a time scale profile maybe a
power Spectrum then of course I need to
better provide better neural phenomenal
connections but then I would go from
there and individual and that maybe that
induction method is the right thing for
you
yeah so that's the way I would
individualize and one thing sorry to
Reign into your parade there's a lot of
aversive effects in meditation
so I'm as a clinical psychiatrist who
wants to apply meditation to psychotic
patient needs to be very much aware of
that
yeah and again last thing so that's
again it's very important who gets those
adverse different so meditation is not
just good can also be bad like
everything like the pseudocybin can be
very good it can be a disaster
well you have the wrong context
yeah so in last comment on that so when
you're in India the people smile on the
mindfulness
because they say that's not meditation
and meditation is not Buddhist and you
also said mindfulness meditation sort of
I think you use the terms
interchangeably it's mainly for let's
say people with anxiety of depression
that's the Western world
meditation has a very different context
when you go to China or India completely
different
yeah so very very important and what is
presenters in mind for okay now I do
five-minute mindfulness and then I'm uh
able and then I'm more capacitive and
can have more success that's not the
context for mindfulness so I'm really I
live over there so I know how they do it
I'm strongly against it it doesn't work
yeah and you can see this is
let us through that context
about the challenging effect of
meditation they are recognized as any
prescription or whatever and has to do
as you say with the with the person and
um who is prescribing the thing so
normally panic attacks and and and yeah
difficult events that happen during
meditation has to do with is very
similar to exercise I mean you normally
if you decide to run a marathon you are
not from nothing going and go to Rana
Marathon because probably you're going
to have some you know some
um problems with your muscles or your
knees or whatever because you are not
prepared so normally you have to
prepare prepare it and go very like
increase the frequency very slow and
everything and normally panics attacks
and all this kind of secondary or what
is called The Dark Knight of the assault
or meditation has to do with these doses
that is people from the West that goes
and from being really like running ahead
with their jobs and everything they sit
and they have this panic attack when
they sit for two weeks or something like
that and also when they are in a very
bad depressive or Society State and they
sit to meditate then they have this
thing so this secondary effects happen
basically for a bad management and
prescription of the technique but it's
not the technique itself
and regarding what you said about the
the how mindfulness is seen in the west
I say that actually that mindfulness was
integrated in there was to make frontal
stress and Lifestyles from the
westerners uh yeah point of view you
know like anxiety depression as kind of
a prescription and in Oriental countries
it's a lifestyle to live like that and
and and that's why I'm saying that how
we what we are trying to achieve is not
this only mindfulness stuff but that's
why I'm
um evoking for something more holistic
that has to do with lifestyles in
general where meditation is one
component that helps you to be aware of
your habits and helps you to change your
habits uh because you become better to
sense yourself and and since the rest of
the people basically yeah thank you
so Rodrigo is not paying attention to
the computer and is absolutely
insightful about the discussions so do
you want to make any questions
now that you have done a review and kind
of characterize the the status quo the
same so I I guess you're getting ready
to kind of start using this approach and
they are wondering about uh red light
whether because freelance has been
Gathering a lot of data and I get from
the existing data will be possible to
draw some of these Arrow static measure
so then are you planning to do that and
so remind me
red light adventure started before the
Copic pandemic or you had started after
we started before because the meaning
that you have before and after yeah but
no because for before we have only
pre-existing data okay that was
collected previously I was wondering
because just wondering would be great
yes well in any case
at least you could look at the because
you have you have environments
thank you Marie yes uh we are planning
to do a lot of things with the plasma
sample the first tool
um we would like to to evaluate the the
the most important or more classic and
neurodegenerative biomarkers
and of course if we but also we want to
evaluate this type of holostatic
biomarkers well if we have money of
course we are going to evaluate
everything but I think that now we have
some preliminary data from the the the
collaboration because the collaboration
with the Andres letepsi and we have this
type of uh immuno inflammatory proteins
but yes some of some of them are related
to this allostatic low biomarker but I
mean we can use it for the renew one and
everything and is here in the in this
web preliminary data we have a healthy
Contours the MCI or the Euro Golf Course
patient and also ID I don't know if we
have some FTD patients but probably and
now we are planning to do something with
uh
um I'm sorry and
we are planning to do something with the
car pounds and with an association with
the NIH and uh yes we are going to have
some preliminary attack for the renewal
of the R1 or the red and I want to add
two things of that we are also starting
to do exposome mediation like social
epigenomics effects in the methylation
and and
many different
epigenetic blocks that by the way many
of those doesn't work in our population
you know it's a very important and
really reported Hispanic Paradox is
scholar so the patients are younger
some clothes related to aging I working
well and showing the strong effects of
the environmental factors accentuating
the chronological game gap sorry this is
one and the other thing is
we want to do allostatic intercepting
Network in all our patients we are going
to do that and we we we just started to
I would say change the idea of
predictive coding in a linear way but
using his special temporal approach and
I want to try it in their static
interceptive Network for for the frontal
temporal dementia patients of course
yeah yeah we are going to do it yes
so now I think it's fantastic value
it's working it does work but I wonder
if you have about this idea of what you
all represented about always happy loads
and mindfulness because
I say once I think so it doesn't work
here of mine also some people is also
work for other but can we go through the
subjective experience of mindfulness to
some objective metrics
that can allow you to identify who is
objectively benefiting really from this
and follow that all because that's
that's not really is very specific
approach is it what do you think yeah I
think would be ideal to be able to do
something like that but
[Music]
um
I'm not sure
yes yeah yeah
um yeah I I think uh you can have I mean
you can have of course you have an
interest subject variation that is like
killing the biomarkers like uh findings
and everything but you have people that
is more successfully regulating and
people that will take more time and
normally you do the studies and you say
Okay
um these people in eight weeks they
didn't manage or they manage or they
have different stressors from the
outside so basically what would you try
would like to do is to do an internal
Mark of one that people is managing
their self-regulation and everything and
so you can use each one as their own
start points and and end points and if
some people need eight weeks good for
them because all programs and in in the
US like mindfulness-based cognitive
therapy is covered for health insurance
and stuff but people needs more time and
people who is under more allostatic load
is going to need a more maybe a steep uh
or not so steep meditation apprentice
apprentice and other people so basically
to make it short I think will be like uh
some internal marker uh when people is
basically regulating and he's in place
with himself and that could be
subjective but will be also nice to have
like a more like biological marker
because people also lie to themselves so
to the more biologically driven uh
approach to efficacy of this particular
intervention yeah but the subjective
part is also very important because
there is people that can be with a lot
of cortisol and they are like yeah they
are doing okay and then they they just
burn out when one day to the other so
how do you say I mean subjected the
ultimate goal
in the community in terms of how we can
really corroborate biologically and if
that happens and everybody equally
vulnerable to implement biological every
influences on mindfulness and if they
are can they carry forward what is
beneficial attack on long press so that
this demolish is lackings
biological to bring the community
together and solve this lower standing
yeah yeah yeah so yeah sure maybe to
start to do some kind of clustering
profile of you know kind of people with
uh subjective and like more lifestyle
stuff and also meditation so you can do
kind of a prediction within a more like
small like yeah group yeah yeah
sure yeah yeah
other questions I think the
computational core are very far away
yeah be centered
hi
[Music]
um
first of all thank you very much to the
speakers uh great talks I was going to
pick up this last discussion uh I think
that I really agree with with Mario that
there's some like biological mechanisms
lacking the relation between the
environmental burden over
neurodegenerative diseases and mental
disorders we can have for example the
case of the depression it's higher in in
higher socioeconomic status countries as
compared to lower socioeconomic status
countries and the same for neurogenitive
diseases right the inverse sorry
reimbursement
so we have some like peripheral
biomarkers that we can use to track
these diseases we have some like Central
mechanisms that are related to these
diseases and these mental disorders but
there there's a lack of the link between
the periphery the environment the
exposome right and the the internal
Central mechanisms in the in the nervous
system so I think for example it's a
it's a good example to use the the case
of uh of meditation because it's a very
uh like specific effect in metabolism
for example we have an increase
modulation of oxygen metabolism in the
brain
is it maybe related to I don't know like
blood brain barrier permeability for
example there is facilitating the the
entrance of oxygen for example and maybe
that could be related I know with apo-e
Gene that is Rachel cardiovascular risk
and permeability as well so all of those
questions like have to be like unified
in a common framework I believe this is
not just a general commentary not a
specific question sure I mean that is
the you know this cognitive
um
I use cognitive
um yes I mean this is basically this
this is this intra individual you know
like uh cognitive protective factors you
know it's like it's the history of the
system that is giving you also that
variability and is the one we can
basically we cannot explain I mean we
want to we want to make it the most
predictable possible so we can take
people on that track but at the end you
don't know we are still modeling this
into individual difference that make
people more resistant or not according
to their lives in general and I think
that your point is is an overall
question so it's happened right now and
we lack theories we lack evidence you
know and it's not only to bring cow cell
explanation it's connecting the leverage
because this is the main Challenge and
it's an academic barrier it's not a it I
mean in nature this happened together
but we have been used to study you know
in a very isolated way I think that we
as we are starting to do it and I see
that theory I I know that yours is not a
fan of the philosophers but we need to
bring theories that can integrate levels
neuroscientists cannot do that at all
home they are not prepared for that on
the contrary they are prepared you know
for the micro level and isolation you
know internal control isolation that's
it well we need here is that really
really integrate the dots we are just
you know doing a small dots of that but
we don't have a common approach for that
because of that I like anastasis by the
way but yeah so don't misunderstand me
I'm not against philosophers I'm against
particular football yeah yeah I know I
know I'm currently dominating in the
Un-American match for the meditation so
that's um we develop what we are going
back to that example so we're going back
we indeed develop a time and space and
self-experience scale
yeah so for meditation same what we do
in schizophrenia yeah because that's a
phenomenological correlate but again I
think probably what you really want and
let's say for the individualization when
I have
a tendency perhaps depression
and are very slow
probably a slow induction technique is
not the right thing
so that's where could be potential
markets yeah and you can try titrate The
Experience yeah doing the different
induction techniques what is the best
one
yeah and that will be an individual
fingerprinting of the induction
techniques I think that's absolutely key
yeah
um and then with that coming there from
the phenomenology
that will definitely give me also some
idea about neural markets of course I
I'm not sure but I don't think that sort
of what we do with the global signal
topography
what I expect of course is clear I like
expect less topographic differentiation
in the global signal meaning all regions
are more homogeneously characterized by
their Global activity
that's why you don't process the inputs
in a more differentiated way because the
brain is not literally more synchronized
so that could be potential markers if
you can link them to your degree of
let's say Duality non-duality
um yeah the degree of environment
self-distinction how much you make a
difference
this is a great this is tension you know
environmental self is you know is across
so many other paths we need to to
connect I think this is this is a very
missing area well again you have any
questions for my Kim
people
yes well it's everything very
interesting
I was thinking about the relationship
between meditation and allostasis
specifically by the modulation of the
insular activity
this is a region the main region of the
allostatic intercepting Network so maybe
this can be a hub of influence from
to meditate and therefore regulate the
activity of the insulin therefore
regulate the activity of studying
perceptive Network therefore regulate
the organs and stabilize the organism
could be this could this be possible how
is the evidence
Associated meditation activity of the
insulin because that is a question
because I reviewed that evidence and
only two papers one Frontiers
made that Association but is that
theoretically um scientifically based
meditational insular regulation
there is a lot of discussions and
normally you will have to you will have
something that support
meditators have more interceptive
awareness
foreign
connectivity but
um there are there is another
yeah so the the short answer is yes but
there is still lack of some
replicability because of the degree of
the training so normally you have these
studies in very Advanced meditators that
are not
they're not the real Lifestyles that we
can achieve living in in in in a city
basically
and with normal jobs and stuff so but
normally yeah you take on the best month
and if that is the case then yes and and
there is a sense of self-sensing and
self-regulation in all the models on the
um there is a self-self awareness and
self-regulation that is increased and
insular participate in this same thing
part of the awareness so I think and and
how to relate to allostasis I think that
it's something that we have been all
thinking I mean one stressor will hit
you in a very different way and how your
internal system is standing right so and
how your internal system is standing
that is you can train to regulate to
keep some kind of consistency in how to
maintain your like mental stability or
emotional stability you can train for
that so when you
um train enough then the stressor will
hit you in a kind of a good shape that
you can absorb this and it's not going
to create some critical point that is
going to to
um to trigger some other you know
Cascade of inflammatory and like that so
you can kind of prepare yourself for
allostatic load
um but yeah so that is what I will yeah
because
I have like a two-step question I'm
gonna make the first one I'm doing the
second one we got the same one it's for
you okay
about the is mindfulness how do you
considered the Micromax effect against
for instance like hyper pockets it's
safe
asking for a friend in attention or
disorder for reasons for you to be like
an inner statement no no I mean Focus
attention you can use an internal or you
can use an external object and doesn't
matter the thing is that you the
exercise is to keep your focus on the
object of choosing and realize that you
distract and come back the the attention
to that and doesn't matter if it's
external or internal you can train both
of them
but there is also some papers coming
from Feldman and a guy that is very like
um
it has a great literature about how the
processing of respiratory Rhythm and
everything and he's doing a
uh animal model of meditator mice
that only regulating the you know the
Rhythm through some drugs manipulating
only the the breathing system he's
making the the ratless anxious and and
perceiving all kind of things so I would
say sure I mean literature shows and
also in meditative Styles you have a
external focus and internal focus and in
terms of like cognitive exercise of
coming back your attention to the focus
will be the same but of course that
there is a link with the breathing that
comes from a more bottom-up point of
view uh that is not that we haven't like
separated yet to establish if there is
some different efficacy in the training
with breathing or with the or with the
external object
and the second one is a short question
for all the speakers and if you have
issues like a keyword like a key idea
that someone that doesn't know anything
like me for instance like a a you know
dealer you can take and make a change in
their lifestyle then most important like
a short
no I don't think that there is something
because it's something that we have been
discussing a lot of the personalization
and you know one solution is not is
working for an individual that is not
working for another
like mindfulness can be very disrupted
for some participant it can be very
helpful I mean very healthy healing a
lot so I I wouldn't bet for for nothing
uh in particular I would say of course
we had you have the least
you can repeated that but this is a
question we tend to think this releases
reversal and can be applied to everybody
and I think that we are going to show
enough for coming very important paper
the risk factors interacts in a very
calorie in the paper interacts in a very
differential different weight in
underrepresented population and the
combination and factors for preventing
or for causing or for influencing the
risk it change everything so yeah but
yeah this is a great question I think
one area called Behavioral Sciences I'm
focusing on that particular area because
everybody shows that there is a capital
awareness knowing what is good for you
and doing so really committed to do that
so the behavioral changes
all developing program that women should
people who all right
and the wedding to developed embark on
actual Community personalized behavioral
change towards Hair Design so you see
that for example
this is because we talk about many of
the decisions we discussed here today
prevention
and there is no prevention we don't
shift people understanding from this
type of Behavioral changes and every
lifestyle factor that could be both bad
but it's so disagree and from there to
the core prescriptive type of mind that
we have in our country where we are very
much focused on children our Premiership
America even management many by the
commercial mention of our medical system
but I think there is a lot of work to
those and Learners about that particular
aspect that you're talking about because
it doesn't really matter how many
solutions we develop how many tools we
provide the people the people and this
is
one of my colleagues actually the
director of the schedule the Center for
Behavioral changes in Harry Potter
University
of the Scottish population actually
about how where people were who what
drivers of brain health uh including all
these things so then I'll ask them a lot
of questions about that and so the
majority of the population were aware of
these changes so but when we ask about
are you ready to go for it people say
these people say yes
and when they have one we say well if I
get sick because you see that the video
is not really prevention it's just pure
I mean nothing people of mind the
reasons
we don't shift people knew about what is
really prevention not only people do our
health systems views and approaches to
that so we are running out of the time
last word Claudia and yours
use the mic
if I have to choose some word be happy
and that's it well I am done
I don't know anything to them
so thank you so much our guests are
going to be here in case you want to
interact with them to make questions for
today right we are both here so we
welcome you to to interact with them
they are making collaborations across
the globe so enjoy them thank you so
much
okay
let's bring to take a picture with your
mind